<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>niorad</title>
    <link>https://niorad.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on niorad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://niorad.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping the Footer at the Bottom with CSS-Grid</title>
      <link>https://niorad.github.io/posts/keeping-footer-bottom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niorad.github.io/posts/keeping-footer-bottom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://niorad.github.io/footer_bottom/title_image.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Title-Image&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point in a project, one gets annoyed by the footer hovering right under the header, because there is no content yet to fill up the space. There also may be some really short pages (like the 404), which might not be long enough to fill the whole browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the footer at the browser&amp;rsquo;s bottom just got a little bit easier with CSS-Grid. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to go with some CSS-trickery, Flexbox or JS, but the Grid-solution is the most elegant and simple in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Inline-Form-Validation</title>
      <link>https://niorad.github.io/posts/inline-form-validation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 21:28:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niorad.github.io/posts/inline-form-validation/</guid>
      <description>Checking the input from a user must always happen on the server, so why check it in the browser beforehand? Because UX. The days of reloading pages with error messages (and therefore erased password-fields) are over, and have been for years. Your users shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to submit a form with missing data.
I want to demonstrate that inline-validation is no rocket-surgery, and that it&amp;rsquo;s doable with a few lines of JS and current web-standards, without any libraries and frameworks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Sailor!</title>
      <link>https://niorad.github.io/posts/hello-sailor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 13:57:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niorad.github.io/posts/hello-sailor/</guid>
      <description>Hello, Sailor! This is my little place for technical tutorials, thoughts, and rants.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>